seed.com 2019-11-03

# Privacy Policy - Seed : Seed

Seed Health, Inc. (“Seed,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) is committed to protecting your personal information and this online and mobile privacy and security policy (“Privacy Policy”) lets you know how your personal information is collected, used, shared, protected, and retained. Our Privacy Policy also explains your rights regarding that information, including how to access and update your personal information, and how you can request us to delete it. Please take a moment to review the terms of our Privacy Policy to get a clear understanding of how we handle your personal information.

By using our Website, you consent to the collection, use, sharing and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We reserve the right to make modifications to this Privacy Policy from time to time to adapt it to any changes in applicable laws or our activities. The date of the latest version of this Privacy Policy is indicated at the end of this Privacy Policy. By continuing to use our Website, you are consenting to any changes to this Privacy Policy.

If you do not agree with any provisions of or changes to this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Website. You may also, at any time, communicate with us using the contact information at the bottom of the page in case you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy.

 **What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our Website or other services?**

  *     * Contact information, such as your name, mailing address, email address, and telephone number
    * Financial payment information, such as credit card, debit card, and other financial payment information
    * Unique identifiers such as username and password
    * Preferences information such as product wish lists, order history, and marketing preferences

 **When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, or enter information on our site. Whether or not you actively supply your personal information to us, our website contains cookies and other features that may collect your information when you visit various pages on our website.

 **How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, browse our website, or use certain other site features in the following ways to:

  *     * Personalize your experience to deliver content and products that most interest you
    * Improve our website in order to better serve you
    * Respond to your questions, comments, and requests
    * Administer a contest, promotion, survey, or other site feature
    * Quickly and securely process your transactions
    * Ask for ratings and reviews of services or products
    * Follow up with you after correspondence (live chat, email, text, or voice inquiries)

We also collect information from and about you to comply with our legal obligations, such as:

  *     * To investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions, unauthorized access to our products and services, and other illegal activities
    * To demonstrate compliance with applicable privacy and data security laws and regulations, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and facilitate the exercise of your privacy rights
    * To comply with incident monitoring, reporting, assessment, and notification requirements

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this Privacy Policy.

 **How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of reasonable security measures when a user places an order, enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information. Our website is also scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

Seed uses reasonable technical and organizational measures required under applicable privacy laws to protect your personal information. Among other security measures, your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and they are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and Seed complies with the security requirements of the credit card Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) Program and compliance is validated annually.  PCI requirements apply to all systems that store, process, or transmit cardholder data.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet or stored on a server can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online. Should we have a data security breach, we will promptly comply with all notice obligations under applicable privacy laws. In keeping with industry guidelines, we will promptly make recommended steps to notify you of the breach.

If you prefer not to transmit your credit card number over the internet, you may contact us using the toll-free number listed on the website from which you want to order. If you have any questions regarding security privacy, you may contact us at [privacy@seed.com](mailto:privacy@seed.com).

 **Tracking Technologies + Cookies**

We and our third-party partners, such as advertising partners, marketing partners, and service providers, use certain technologies such as cookies and pixels to track activity on our site. These technologies are used for purposes such as analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site, and gathering demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual basis (that is, reports of your own activity) as well as on an aggregated basis (that is, reports of all user activity or activity of certain users as a group).

These technologies may also identify your location if you choose to share this information with us. Please note that some mobile applications may automatically collect the location of your mobile device using technologies such as GPS, WiFi, or cell tower technology. Most mobile devices allow you to withdraw your permission to provide location data to us in your device settings.

This information can help us improve your access to our website and identify repeat visitors. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to enter a password more than once, thereby saving you time and providing a better experience. Cookies also help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services.

You can withdraw or modify your consent to our use of cookies at any time. If you no longer wish to receive cookies you can use your web browser settings to accept, refuse and delete cookies. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “Help”, “Tools” or “Edit” settings). Please note that if you set your browser to refuse cookies, you may not be able to use all the features of the Seed website.

Seed uses [Cookiebot](https://www.cookiebot.com/), a registered trademark of Cybot, to make our cookie and online tracking GDPR compliant. Cookiebot is designed as a service to facilitate compliance with EU regulations concerning the use of cookies on a company’s website and to help it obtain the relevant consents to the use of cookies from the users of the website. Cookiebot asks users of seed.com for a consent that covers all of our domains (a “Bulk Consent”) on the user’s first visit to any of our websites. Seed has the necessary rights to include such websites on the “domain list”. The functionality of the Bulk Consent is dependent on the user’s acceptance of third-party cookies in the web browser used to access seed.com.

The Bulk Consent is logged and documented by registration of the user’s anonymized IP number, browser user agent, website URL, date and time of consent and a unique, encrypted key that is stored in a data center with Cybot’s cloud vendor, Microsoft Ireland Operations Ltd in Dublin, Ireland. After 12 months, the Bulk Consent is automatically deleted from Cybot’s log and then used only in an aggregated, anonymized form as part of the statistics that Seed has access to in Cookiebot.

Once a month Cookiebot will perform an automated cookie audit by scanning seed.com for cookies (HTTP/Javascript cookies, HTML5 Local Storage, Flash Local Shared Object, Silverlight Isolated Storage, IndexedDB, ultrasound beacons, pixel tags) and generate a cookie declaration with descriptions on every cookie found on the website.

 **Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personal information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

 **Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

 **Sharing of personal information**

We may share your personal information to certain third parties listed below. Please note that once we share your personal information with a third party, it becomes subject to such third party’s privacy practices, though we use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that your personal information is used by such third parties in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

  *     *  **Affiliates** : We may share your personal information with our affiliates to perform services on our behalf or for us
    *  **Service providers** : Your personal information may be shared with third parties acting on our behalf or for us, such as marketing and mailing platforms, Customer relationship management (CRM), and email providers
    *  **Business transfer** : We may share and transfer your personal information without your express permission where there is a corporate event requiring such transfer, such as a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or sale of assets
    *  **Other parties with your consent** : Where you’ve expressly consented for your personal information to be shared with other third parties, we will share it in accordance with such consent
    *  **Legal or administrative process** : We may share your personal information with third parties if we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce this Privacy Policy, to detect or prevent fraud, security, or technical issues, or to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request.

Please note that your personal information may be processed in any country of the world in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and if so, that law enforcement agencies as well as national security agencies of any such countries may have access to it.

 **Your control over your personal information**

  *     * You may decline to share certain personal information with us, in which case we may not be able to fulfill your product requests or provide to you some of our services. For example, we need your email address to authenticate you and perform account services such as password resets, or to provide you with customer support
    * You may decline to accept cookies, but that decision may affect the functionality and performance of our website
    * You may update or correct your personal information at any time by accessing the account settings page on our website, seed.com/account
    * You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from Seed by using the unsubscribe link within each marketing email, or by contacting [care@seed.com](mailto:care@seed.com)
    * You may request information about, and access to, the personal data that we collect from you
    * You may ask questions or make complaints about our privacy and data security practices with regard to your personal data
    * You may request that we delete information that we have collected about you
    * You may ask us for a copy of the information that we collected from you

To exercise any of these options, or for additional information about our privacy and data security practices, please contact us at [privacy@seed.com](mailto:privacy@seed.com).

 **California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach extends well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States of America (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personal information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared.

 **In compliance with CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**

  *     * Users can visit our site anonymously
    * We will maintain a link to our Privacy Policy on our home page
    * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on our home page
    * You will be notified of any material changes to our Privacy Policy on our Privacy Policy page

There are two ways to change your personal information:

  *     * Email us at [care@seed.com](mailto:care@seed.com)
    * Sign in to your account at [seed.com/account](https://seed.com/account)

 **COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

Our site is not intended for use by children under the age of 13. Seed does not knowingly collect or use any personal information from such children. If you are under the age of 13, do not submit any information through our site. If we learn that we collected personal information from children under the age of 13, we will take steps to promptly delete that information. If you believe that a child under age 13 may have provided us with personal information, please contact us at [privacy@seed.com](mailto:privacy@seed.com).

 **CAN-SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you may email us at [care@seed.com](mailto:care@seed.com) and we will promptly remove you from all correspondence.

 **Global Reach**

Seed is a U.S.-based company that has operations and service providers in the United States and internationally. As a result, personal information that we collect may be transferred to our U.S. offices to permit us to comply with our legal, contractual, and business obligations and activities. In addition, we may provide information to third-party service providers in the U.S. and in other countries to the extent necessary to support Seed’s business activities, and we may access personal information collected by our customers to support the services that we provide to our customers. Thus, personal information may be transferred to and stored on servers located in the United States and in countries different from the country in which that information was initially collected. Similarly, information we collect may be accessed by Seed and our third-party service providers and business partners from countries other than the ones in which the information is stored. You consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which Seed or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

 **General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** ****

The GDPR is an European Union (EU) regulation to improve the protection of the personal information and data of EU citizens and increase the obligations of entities who collect or process personal data. These new regulations took effect on May 25, 2018. The regulations greatly enhance the data privacy and security of our EU customers and extend to them exercisable rights enabling greater control over one’s personal information. EU residents can learn more specific information about their privacy rights[here](https://www.seed.com/privacy/gdpr).

 **Data Retention and Deletion** ****

We retain your personal information only as long as necessary to accomplish the business purpose for which it was collected, or to comply with our legal and contractual obligations.   Afterwards, we will securely dispose such personal information, as required by applicable law.

 **Governing Law**

This Privacy Policy shall be interpreted and governed by the laws of the State of California. The courts located in Los Angeles, California, shall have sole and exclusive jurisdiction to hear any claims or disputes arising out of this Privacy Policy.

 **If you feel that we are not abiding by this Privacy Policy, you should contact us immediately via:**

  *     * Telephone at 844-646-3586
    * Email at [privacy@seed.com](mailto:privacy@seed.com)
